Kael mss., 1939-2001 LMC 3004
Lilly Library
Kael mss.
ca. 1939-2001
Lilly Library
Kael, Pauline.
LMC 3004
172.5 Linear Feet 114 boxes, 12 oversize, 3 oversize folio
The Kael mss., ca. 1939-2001, consists of the papers and correspondence of film critic and author Pauline Kael, 1919-2001.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 2007
Biographical Note
Pauline Kael, 1919-2001, was an American film critic and author. She was born on June 19, 1919 in Petaluma, California. Her family moved to San Francisco when she was eight. She attended the University of California, Berkeley from 1936-1940 during which time she broadcast film reviews on radio station KPFA and managed the Berkeley Cinema Guild Theaters. In 1965 she moved permanently to the east coast where she freelanced for various magazines such as Life and New Republic. McCall's hired her briefly as a full-time film critic, but it was rumored that she was fired for writing a scathing review of The Sound of Music. Kael was best known as the film critic for The New Yorker where she was hired in 1968. She resigned in 1979 to become executive consultant on film projects for Paramount Pictures Corporation. She soon became disenchanted and returned to The New Yorker in 1980 where she stayed until her retirement in 1991. She published numerous books. Most were compilations of her New Yorker columns, including I Lost it at the Movies, Kiss Kiss Bang Bang, Going Steady, Deeper Into Movies, Reeling, When the Lights Go Down, Hooked, Movie Love, and For Keeps. One of her lengthier columns in The New Yorker became the basis for her book The Citizen Kane Book: Raising Kane which also contained the shooting script for the film. She received numerous awards for her criticism: The 1970 American Academy of Arts and Letters award for literature, The National Book Award in 1974, as well as awards from P.E.N. in 1996 and the 1999 National Book Critics Circle's Ivan Sandrof Award. In addition, she received honorary degrees from various colleges and universities. Kael died on September 3, 2001 at the age of 82.
Scope and Content Note
The correspondence is comprised of personal letters from colleagues and friends, those relating to her writings, and many fan letters. Very few copies of Kael's own letters are present. The Director's files contain notes taken by Kael during the film screenings, typescript or holograph drafts of articles about the films by Kael and others, and related materials such as press kits, stills and clippings. The Writings section includes holograph drafts, typescripts and notes for her articles and books, as well as research and production materials, and advertisements. Files concerning her stint at KPFA and tear sheets of most of her "Current Cinema" columns are also present. Screenplays and play scripts submitted for her perusal make up most of the Writings by Others section. Kael clipped thousands of articles from magazines and newspapers. These clippings comprise the bulk of the Subjects file. Items in the Memorabilia section include Kael's awards, certificates and diplomas, programs from various film festivals and photographs. Among the audio-visual tapes are recordings from KPFA broadcasts.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series: I. Correspondence; II. Directors; III. Writings by Kael; IV. Writings by Others; V. Subjects; VI. Memorabilia; VII. Audiovisual. An inventory is available.
Film critics--United States.; Motion pictures--Reviews.; Motion picture producers and directors.; Motion picture plays.; Motion picture film; Film Posters; Kael, Pauline--Correspondence.
- I. Correspondence
  Arrangement
  Arranged into two sections: Alphabetical and Chronological. Each name in the Alphabetical section is followed by the year or range of years of the correspondence. Some related materials may also be present, such as photographs or printed materials.
  Scope and Contents
  The Chronological section is not indexed. Additional correspondence may be found throughout the collection.
  - Alphabetical
    - Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences., 1993 (Box 1)
    - Adamson, Joe., 1971-2000 (Box 1)
    - Adler, Larry., 1991-1994 (Box 1)
    - Albarino, Richard., 1979 (Box 1)
    - Alda, Rutanya., 1978-1982 (Box 1)
    - Alexander, Shana., 1970-1994 (Box 1)
    - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1965-1999 (Box 1)
    - Allen, David., 1979-1982 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Linda., 1987-2000; (5 folders) (Box 1)
    - Allen, Woody., 1971-1975 (Box 1)
    - Alsina Thevenet, Homero., 1963 (Box 1)
    - Altman, Robert., 1973-1976; 1984 (Box 1)
    - American Film., 1981-1984 (Box 1)
      General
      (see also: Aufderheide, Pat)
    - The American Film Institute., 1969-1973 (Box 1)
    - Anderson, Wes., 1998 (Box 1)
    - Anger, Kenneth., 1977; 1982 (Box 1)
    - Arango, Pedro L., 1978-1979 (Box 1)
    - Arkoff, Samuel Z., 1975-1981 (Box 1)
    - Arnold, Gary H., 1962-1977; (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Arthur, Jean., 1973 (Box 1)
    - The Atlantic Monthly., 1965-1999 (Box 1)
    - Auerbach, Nina., 1988-1995 (Box 1)
    - Aufderheide, Pat., 1980-1987 (Box 1)
    - Avedon, Richard., 1972-1994 (Box 1)
    - Bacon, Kevin., 1982-1984 (Box 1)
    - Bacon, Martha Sherman., 1950-1955; 1974-1976; (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Badham, John M., 1977 (Box 1)
    - Baez, Joan., 1978 (Box 1)
    - Baillie, Bruce., 1963-1966 (Box 1)
    - Bantam Books Inc., 1971-1977 (Box 1)
    - Barrie, George., 1977-1978 (Box 1)
    - Baum, Thomas., 1996-2000 (Box 1)
    - Bazink, Marta J., 1986 (Box 1)
    - Benson, Sheila., 1980-1997 (Box 1)
    - Bergstein, Eleanor., 1975; 1998 (Box 1)
    - Bernhard, Sandra., 1984 (Box 1)
    - Bertolucci, Bernardo., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Bishop, Chris and Lizzie Zbigniew., 1962-1963 (Box 1)
    - Blackman, Stephen, Maria Dolores and Alan., 1980-2000 (Box 1)
    - Blatty, William Peter., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Blount, Roy., 1972-1991 (Box 1)
    - Bogarde, Dirk., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Bokaer, Tsvi., 1971-2000 (Box 1)
    - Boorman, John., 1974-1997 (Box 1)
    - Boyar, Jay M., 1974-1991 (Box 1)
    - Bradbury, Ray., 1966-1969 (Box 1)
    - Brantley, Will., 1979-1999 (Box 1)
    - Braudy, Leo., 1973-1982 (Box 1)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC)., 1972-1991 (Box 1)
    - The British Film Institute., 1954-1955; 1972-1982; 1991 (Box 1)
    - Brody, Meredith., 1978-2000; (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Brooks, Louise., 1962-1968; 1986 (Box 1)
    - Broughton, James., 1965-1967 (Box 1)
    - Brown, Helen Gurly., 1972-1975 (Box 1)
    - Brown, Rita Mae., 1978 (Box 1)
    - Brownlow, Kevin., 1968 (Box 1)
    - Burnett, Carol., 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - Burstyn, Ellen., 1971 (Box 1)
    - Butler, Brett., 1990 (Box 1)
    - Button, John & Scott Burton., 1962-1963 (Box 1)
    - Cahill, Thomas and Susan Jane Neunzig., 1978-1979; 1997-2000 (Box 1)
    - Carr, Carol., 1989-2000 (Box 1)
    - Castilla, Sergio, 1939-2001 (Box 1)
    - Cebulski, Frank., 1974-1984 (Box 1)
    - Chappetta, Robert., 1966-1992; (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Chasman, David., 1975-2000; (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Chin, Daryl., 1978-2001; (4 folders) (Box 2)
    - Christiansen, Richard., 1968-1979 (Box 2)
    - Chute, David., 1980-1989 (Box 2)
    - Clinton, Bill., 1980 (Box 2)
    - Coates, Paul & Anne., 1985-2000; (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Columbia Pictures Industries, Inc., 1978-1986 (Box 2)
    - Commentary., 1954 (Box 2)
    - Condon, Bill., 1981 (Box 2)
    - Coppola, Francis Ford., 1999 (Box 2)
    - Corwin, Norman., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Crawford, Richard., 1974-2000; (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Crichton, Michael., 1972-1974 (Box 2)
    - Croce, Arlene., 1967-1991; (2 folders) (Box 2)
      interview by Susie Linfield for Dance Ink
    - Crowe, Cameron., 1982; 1989 (Box 2)
    - Curtis Brown, Ltd., 1976-2000 (Box 2)
    - Dahl, Roald., 1977 (Box 2)
    - De Antonio, Emile., 1963-1964; 1980 (Box 2)
    - Delrogh, Dennis., 1977-1991 (Box 2)
    - Demme, Jonathan., 1986-1993 (Box 2)
    - Denby, David., 1969-1999 (Box 2)
    - Dietrich, Marlene., 1983 (Box 2)
    - Di Piero, W. S., 1975-1977 (Box 2)
    - Donovan, Arlene., 1971-2000 (Box 2)
    - Dortmund, Erhard K. and Elke., 1972-2001; (5 folders) (Box 2)
    - Drischell, Gwyn and Ralph., 1989-2000 (Box 2)
    - Duffell, Peter., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Duffy, Trent., 1983-1999 (Box 2)
    - Duncan, Robert., 1940-1974; (13 folders) (Box 2)
    - Dunne, John Gregory., 1972-1977 (Box 2)
    - Eastwood, Clint., 1977 (Box 3)
    - Ebert, Roger., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Edelstein, David., 1991-1998 (Box 3)
    - Ehrenstein, David., 1989-1994 (Box 3)
    - Eisner, Michael D., 1979 (Box 3)
    - Elliott, David., 1973-2001; (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - Ellison, Harlan., 1976 (Box 3)
    - Embry, Norris., 1954-1974 (Box 3)
    - Ephron, Nora., 1979 (Box 3)
    - Epstein, Bob., 1988-1989 (Box 3)
    - Espen, Hal., 1991-1999 (Box 3)
    - Fadimon, Clifton., 1967 (Box 3)
    - Farber, Manny., 1976-2001 (Box 3)
    - Feeney, Mark., 1982-2001 (Box 3)
    - Forbes, Malcolm S., 1983-1984 (Box 3)
    - Foundas, Scott., 1996-2001 (Box 3)
    - Fowler, Robert., 1981; 1983 (Box 3)
    - Fox, William Price., 1979-1986 (Box 3)
    - Friedenbach, Jim., 1983-1993 (Box 3)
    - Friel., 1987 (Box 3)
    - Frost, Polly., 1982-1988 (Box 3)
    - Frye, E. Max., 1995 (Box 3)
    - Fuentes, Carlos., 1977 (Box 3)
    - Gaffney, Jace., 1972-2001; (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - Garelick, Jon., 1975-1998; (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - Garfield, Allen., 1975-1986 (Box 3)
    - Getchell, Robert., 1972-2001; (7 folders) (Box 3)
    - Gibson, Henry., 1975-2000 (Box 3)
    - Ginsburg, Vi, undated; (see: Rosenberg, Vi) (Box 3)
    - Gleason, Ralph J., 1970-1974 (Box 3)
    - Gleiberman, Owen., 1979-1982 (Box 3)
    - Goldin, Marilyn., 1971-1974 (Box 3)
    - Goldman, Bo., 1980-1991 (Box 3)
    - Goldstein, Sydney., 1980-2000 (Box 3)
    - Greenberg, Joel., 1963; 1969 (Box 3)
    - Griswold, Jeff., 1975-1992; (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Guare, John., 1979 (Box 3)
    - Haines, Fred., 1962-1999 (Box 3)
    - Hallowell, John., 1973-1990 (Box 3)
    - Halper, Albert., 1971 (Box 3)
    - Hamilton, James., 1976-2000; (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - Hampton, Howard., 1992-2000; (4 folders) (Box 4)
    - Hannah, Don., 1977-2001; (5 folders) (Box 4)
    - Harper & Row, Publishers, Inc., 1971; 1981; 1985 (Box 4)
    - Harrington, Curtis., 1972-1975 (Box 4)
    - Hecht, Harold., 1976 (Box 4)
    - Hellman, Lillian., 1973 (Box 4)
    - Henske, Judy and Craig Doerge., 1979-2000; (5 folders) (Box 4)
    - Herring, Hubert B., 1976 (Box 4)
    - Hill, George Roy., 1969 (Box 4)
    - Hinson, Hal., 1979-1997 (Box 4)
    - Hirschman, Jack., 1962-1971 (Box 4)
    - Hislop, Alan., 1965-1974 (Box 4)
    - Horan, Robert., 1941-1955 (Box 4)
    - Horsley, Jake., 1997-2001 (Box 4)
    - Houseman, John., 1971 (Box 4)
    - Howe, Irving., 1963-1983 (Box 4)
    - Hudson, Luke., 1992-2001 (Box 4)
    - Hunter, Evan., 1966 (Box 4)
    - Hurley, Joseph., 1970-1984 (Box 4)
    - Huston, John and Angelica., 1976-1987 (Box 4)
    - Ivory, James., 1975 (Box 4)
    - Jabbar, Javed., 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - Jacobus, Harry., 1989-1992 (Box 4)
    - Jaffe, Stanley R., 1980 (Box 4)
    - Jaglom, Henry., 1973 (Box 4)
    - James, Clive., 1977-1980 (Box 4)
    - James, Gina and Will., 1980 (Box 4)
    - Janeway, Elizabeth., 1971 (Box 4)
    - Jebb, Julian., 1974-1984 (Box 4)
    - Jenkins, Bruce., 1992 (Box 4)
    - Jewison, Norman., 1972 (Box 4)
    - Joffé, Roland., 1985 (Box 4)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation., 1968-2000 (Box 4)
    - Johnson, Lamont., 1974-1981 (Box 4)
    - Johnson, Nunnally., 1968-1971 (Box 4)
    - Joseph, Rudolph S., 1971 (Box 4)
    - Justema, William., 1974-1987; (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - Jutra, Claude., 1962-1977 (Box 4)
    - Kael, Cecelia., 1983-1986 (Box 4)
    - Kael family - various., 1976-1988 (Box 4)
    - Kareda, Urjo., 1971-1991 (Box 4)
    - Kasden, Lawrence., 1977 (Box 4)
    - Kauffman, Stanley., 1961-1962 (Box 4)
    - Kaufman, Jeff & Julie Kirgo., 1977-2000; (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Kaufman, Philip., 1983 (Box 4)
    - Kay, Burf., 1976-1981 (Box 4)
    - Kazan, Elia., 1974 (Box 4)
    - Keillor, Garrison., 1990-1991 (Box 4)
    - Keith, Brian., 1975 (Box 4)
    - Kershner, Irvin., 1962-2001; (4 folders) (Box 4)
    - Kizer, Carolyn., 1984 (Box 5)
    - Klawans, Stuart., 1990-1992 (Box 5)
    - Klein, Colleen., 1990-2000; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Knelman, Martin., 1971-1987 (Box 5)
    - Koch, Howard., 1968-1976 (Box 5)
    - Koning, Hans (formerly: Hans Koningsberger)., 1968-1979 (Box 5)
    - Korman, Harvey., 1991 (Box 5)
    - Korty, John., 1973; 1977; 1986 (Box 5)
    - Kosinki, Jerzy., 1978 (Box 5)
    - Kosleck, Martin., 1970-1973 (Box 5)
    - Kramer, Richard., 1974-1998; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Labro, Philippe., 1972 (Box 5)
    - Lange, Jessica., 1977 (Box 5)
    - Lasky, Melvin., 1978 (Box 5)
    - Lauter, Ed., 1974; 1977 (Box 5)
    - Lebedoff, David., 1984-1988 (Box 5)
    - Lehrman, Jack., 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Lerman, Leo., 1973-1991 (Box 5)
    - Lesser, Wendy., 1980-1992 (Box 5)
    - Lithgow, John., 1982 (Box 5)
    - Littlejohn, David., 1972-1976 (Box 5)
    - Loomis, Richard M., 1947-1965; 1977-1988; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Loos, Anita., 1971-1973 (Box 5)
    - Losey, Joseph., 1974-1975 (Box 5)
    - Lynch, David., 1980-1986 (Box 5)
    - McCarthy, Mary., 1970 (Box 5)
    - McCrea, Joel., 1972 (Box 5)
    - McDowell, Roddy., 1966; 1972 (Box 5)
    - McKuen, Rod., 1969 (Box 5)
    - McMurtry, Larry., 1992 (Box 5)
    - McNamara, Ed., 1975-1977 (Box 5)
    - Mailer, Norman., 1971-1973 (Box 5)
    - Malko, George., 1974-2000; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Malle, Louis., 1981-1989 (Box 5)
    - Mallery, David., 1967-2000; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Mandel, Robert., 1984; 1987 (Box 5)
    - Manrique, Jaime., 1973-2000; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Marcus, Alan., 1962-1978; 1992; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Marcus, Greil., 1973-2001; (5 folders) (Box 5)
    - Marion Boyars Publishers Ltd., 1976-2000 (Box 5)
    - Marmostein, Gary., 1978-2001 (Box 5)
    - Massey, Erica Rae., 1983-1985 (Box 5)
    - Matthau, Walter., 1971-1980 (Box 5)
    - Maurice Temple Smith Ltd., 1970-1971 (Box 5)
    - Mayer, Arthur & Lillie., 1964-1979 (Box 5)
    - Mazursky, Paul., 1969; 1985 (Box 5)
    - Menaker, Dan., 1975-2000 (Box 5)
    - Meyer, Nicholas., 1976-1977 (Box 5)
    - Millar, Gavin., 1977-1979 (Box 5)
    - Minckler, David., 1976-1991 (Box 5)
    - Mitchell, Elvis., 1980-1988; (3 folders) (Box 5)
    - Mitchell, Vi (see: Rosenberg, Vi), undated (Box 5)
    - Moad, Daryl., 1979-2001 (Box 5)
    - The Modern Review., 1991 (Box 5)
    - Montalban, Ricardo., 1982 (Box 5)
    - Morgenstern, Joseph., 1975-1998; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Moriarty, Michael., 1992 (Box 5)
    - Mouris, Frank and Caroline., 1981-1984 (Box 5)
    - Murphy, Kathleen., 1999 (Box 5)
    - Murray, Bill., 1987 (Box 5)
    - Myers, Michael Scott., 1998 (Box 5)
    - Narizzano, Silvio., 1977 (Box 6)
    - Nasatir, Marcia., 1969-1999 (Box 6)
    - Nelson, Ken., 1972-1998 (Box 6)
    - The New Republic., 1965-1999 (Box 6)
    - New York Magazine., 1978-1987 (Box 6)
    - The New York Review of Books., 1963-1995 (Box 6)
    - The New York Times., 1964-1990 (Box 6)
    - New York Women in Film & Television., 1981; 1993 (Box 6)
    - The New Yorker., 1970-2000; (6 folders) (Box 6)
    - Newman, Paul., 1984 (Box 6)
    - Ney, Joanna., 1980-2000 (Box 6)
    - Nyblom, Ragna., 1960-1961; 1969 (Box 6)
    - Oberon, Merle., 1972-1973 (Box 6)
    - The Observer., 1970; 1973; 1977; 1991 (Box 6)
    - Olle, Linda., 1979-1997 (Box 6)
    - Ophuls, Marcel., 1975 (Box 6)
    - Osborn, Robert (Chesley)., 1974-1985 (Box 6)
    - Owens, Iris., 1975-1980 (Box 6)
    - Paramount Pictures., 1977-1992 (Box 6)
    - Parrish, Robert., 1994 (Box 6)
    - Partisan Review., 1954-1955 (Box 6)
    - Patterson, Richard., 1977 (Box 6)
    - Payne, Alexander., 1999 (Box 6)
    - Pechter, William S., 1961-1998 (Box 6)
    - Peck, Gregory., 1984-1985 (Box 6)
    - Peckinpah, Sam., 1970-1976 (Box 6)
    - Petaluma Area Chamber of Commerce., 1992 (Box 6)
    - Pollack, Sydney., 1973 (Box 6)
    - Pollak, Richard., 1974-1999 (Box 6)
    - Post, Ted., 1975 (Box 6)
    - Quinn, Kathleen., 1988-2000 (Box 6)
    - Rafferty, Terence., 1985-1991 (Box 6)
    - Rainer, Peter., 1970-2000 (Box 6)
    - Raphaelson, Samson and Dorshka., 1977-1994; (6 folders) (Box 6)
    - Ray, Satyajit., 1976 (Box 6)
    - Reed, Rex., 1968 (Box 6)
    - Reiner, Carl., 1970 (Box 6)
    - Renoir, Jean and Dido., 1961-1985 (Box 6)
    - Rich, Frank., 1977-1994 (Box 6)
    - Richardson, Tony., 1981 (Box 6)
    - Rickey, Carrie., 1975-1986 (Box 6)
    - Ridgway, Rick., 1992-2001; (3 folders) (Box 6)
    - Ritt, Martin., 1972 (Box 6)
    - Ritz, Harry & Naomi., 1973-1996; (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Rorem, Ned., 1975-2000 (Box 7)
    - Rose, Lloyd., 1975-2000; (7 folders) (Box 7)
    - Rosenberg, Violet., 1939-1947; (7 folders); date: 1973-1996, (Box 7)
    - Ross, Livia., 1981-1989 (Box 7)
    - Roth, Bobby., 1985-1997 (Box 7)
    - Rotha, Paul., 1975-1982 (Box 7)
    - Rydell, Mark., 1979 (Box 7)
    - Sales, Grover., 1966-2001 (Box 7)
    - Salter, James., 1969 (Box 7)
    - Sarne, Michael., 1968 (Box 7)
    - The Saturday Review., 1972-1985 (Box 7)
    - Sawhill, Ray., 1974-2000; (4 folders) (Box 7)
    - Schaefer, Stephen., 1977-1978; 1984 (Box 7)
    - Schickel, Richard., 1969; 1983 (Box 7)
    - Schrader, Paul., 1968-1976; 1991-1993; (3 folders) (Box 7)
    - Schwartz, Sanford., 1975-2000 (Box 7)
    - Scott, Ridley., 1982 (Box 7)
    - Scully, Robert Guy., 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - Segal, Erich., 1971-1973 (Box 7)
    - Seldes, George., 1971; 1982 (Box 7)
    - Seligman, Craig., 1981-1998; (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - Sepulveda, Ralph., 1973-1981 (Box 7)
    - Seydor, Paul., 1983; 1996 (Box 7)
    - Shull, Leo., 1971; 1986 (Box 7)
    - Siegel, Joel E., 1966-1969 (Box 7)
    - Sigal, Clancy., 1973-1994 (Box 7)
    - Sight and Sound., 1955-1964 (Box 7)
    - Simmons, Charles Paul., 1996-1997 (Box 7)
    - Singular, Stephen., 1984-1985 (Box 7)
    - Sjöman, Vilgot., 1967-1977 (Box 7)
    - Slattery, William J., 1989-1992 (Box 7)
    - Smirnoff, Marc., 1984-1998 (Box 7)
    - Smith, Bradley F., 1974-1989 (Box 7)
    - Smith, Lee., 1994 (Box 7)
    - Smith, Liz (Mary Elizabeth)., 1971-1982 (Box 7)
    - Solow, Martin., 1972-1979 (Box 7)
    - Sontag, Susan., 1963; 1973 (Box 7)
    - Sorel, Edward., 1986; 1996 (Box 7)
    - Southern, Terry., 1988 (Box 7)
    - Spielberg, Steven., 1974-1977 (Box 7)
    - Spottiswoode, Roger., 1983 (Box 7)
    - Springer, John., 1968-1984 (Box 7)
    - Sragow, Michael Howard and Glenda Hobbs., 1973-1984; (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - Sragow, Michael Howard...(cont.)., 1985-2001; (3 folders) (Box 8)
    - Stanton, Harry Dean., 1975 (Box 8)
    - Stark, Ray., 1968-1984 (Box 8)
    - Steegmuller, Francis., 1968-1976 (Box 8)
    - Stern, Phil., 1988; 1993 (Box 8)
    - Stiller, Jerry and Anne Meara., 1983; 1987; 1991 (Box 8)
    - Stoller, James., 1962-1963 (Box 8)
    - Strand, Chick., 1962-1997 (Box 8)
    - Sullivan, Gwyn., 1978-1997 (Box 8)
    - Susann, Jacqueline., 1971 (Box 8)
    - Swaim, Bob., 1988 (Box 8)
    - Terkel, Studs., 1968-1971 (Box 8)
    - Tevis, Eleanora., 1986 (Box 8)
    - Toback, James., 1978 (Box 8)
    - Towne, Robert., 1982-1983; 1989 (Box 8)
    - Trumbo, Dalton., 1970 (Box 8)
    - United Artists Corporation., 1971-1977 (Box 8)
    - University of California - Berkeley., 1971-1973 (Box 8)
    - Valenti, Jack., 1967-1983 (Box 8)
    - The Village Voice., 1979-2000 (Box 8)
    - Vineberg, Steve., 1984-2001 (Box 8)
    - Wagnenknecht, Edward., 1963 (Box 8)
    - Walken, Christopher., 1979 (Box 8)
    - Wallach family (Bret, Jed, Chris, Sandro, Maya)., 1975-1999 (Box 8)
    - Walsh, Robert., 1989-1991 (Box 8)
    - Wanamaker, Sam., 1981 (Box 8)
    - Warren, Leslie Ann., 1985 (Box 8)
    - Warthen, John., 1970-1997 (Box 8)
    - Webster, Ivan., 1972-1977; 1994 (Box 8)
    - Weeks, Edward., 1972 (Box 8)
    - West, Rebecca., 1976 (Box 8)
    - Whitaker, Forest., 1986 (Box 8)
    - White, Armond., 1976-1999 (Box 8)
    - White, William Anthony Parker., 1963 (Box 8)
    - Whitmore, Stanford., 1971-1975 (Box 8)
    - Wilder, Gene., 1975 (Box 8)
    - Wilson, Chuck., 1990-2001; (3 folders) (Box 8)
    - Wolcott, James., 1975-1991 (Box 8)
    - Writer's Guild of America., 1971-1982 (Box 8)
    - Yates, George Worthing., 1971 (Box 8)
    - York, Michael., 1972 (Box 8)
    - Young, Colin., 1975-1998 (Box 8)
    - Young, Vernon., 1960-1962 (Box 8)
    - Zarem Inc., 1977-1990; (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - Zuberano, Maurice., 1988-1993 (Box 8)
    - Zwigoff, Terry., 1995 (Box 8)
  - Chronological
    - 1942-1966 (Box 8:)
    - 1967-1973, Oct. (Box 9:)
    - 1973, Nov. - 1976, Sept. (Box 10:)
    - 1976, Oct. - 1979, Feb. (Box 11:)
    - 1979, Mar. - 1982, July (Box 12:)
    - 1982, Aug. - 1985 (Box 13:)
    - 1986-1990 (Box 14:)
    - 1991-2001, undated (Box 15:)
- II. Directors
  Aranged alphabetically by director. Film titles are listed alphabetically under director's name. One folder per film title or subject, unless otherwise indicated.
  The notes may be those taken by Kael, holographs or typescripts of her reviews, and/or articles by Kael and others. The photographs are mostly stills. Printed items are generally "Cinema Texas program notes" (University of Texas at Austin) or "The Art Film" containing descriptive notes often written by Kael. Programs are printed programs or descriptions of a film for film festivals and other showings. Clippings may also include photocopies or print-outs of articles from the internet. Oversize materials are filed in Boxes 113-116, 121 and 124.
  - Abrahams, Jim, undated (Box 16)
    - Big Business., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 16)
  - Abrahams, Jim, David Zucker, Jerry Zucker (Box 16)
    - Airplane!, notes, publicity, clippings (Box 16)
    - Ruthless People., notes, press kit, clippings (Box 16)
    - Top Secret!, clippings (Box 16)
  - Ackeren, Robert van (Box 16)
    - Die Flambierete Frau (A Woman in Flames - U.S.)., press kit, clippings (Box 16)
  - Adelson, Alan and Kate Taverna (Box 16)
    - Lodz Ghetto., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 16)
  - Adler, Lou (Box 16)
    - Ladies and Gentlemen, the Fabulous Stains (aka: All Washed Up)., notes, script (Box 16)
  - Adlon, Percy (Box 16)
    - Sugar Baby., press kit, clippings (Box 16)
    - Clippings concerning other films (Box 16)
  - Akkad, Moustapha (Box 16)
    - Lion of the Desert., clippings (Box 16)
  - Alda, Alan (Box 16)
    - The Four Seasons., notes, clippings (Box 16)
    - Sweet Liberty., notes, press kit, clippings (Box 16)
    - Clippings concerning other films and Alda (Box 16)
  - Aldrich, Robert (Box 16)
    - The Choirboys., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 16)
    - The Dirty Dozen., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 16)
    - The Flight of the Phoenix., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 16)
    - The Frisco Kid., notes, clippings (Box 16)
    - Hustle., notes, press release, publicity (Box 16)
    - The Killing of Sister George., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 16)
    - The Legend of Lylah Clare., notes, publicity, printed item, clippings (Box 16)
    - The Longest Yard., clippings (Box 16)
    - Twilight's Last Gleaming., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 16)
    - Ulzana's Raid., publicity, clippings (Box 16)
    - Clippings concerning other films (Box 16)
    - Materials concerning Aldrich (Box 16)
  - Aleksandrov, Grigori and Sergei M. Eisenstein (Box 16)
    - Time in the Sun., programs, photographs, clippings (Box 16)
      (see also: Box 113)
  - Algar, James (Box 16)
    - Seal Island., photographs (Box 16)
  - Algar, James, et al. (Box 16)